you were captured by the Tatar-Mongols in 1238
вас в 1238 году захватили татаро-монгол
Yes When you freed yourself, here is the year and day
Да Когда вы освободились вот год день
when you declared independence from the
когда вы провозгласили независимость от
Golden Horde If not, then you are
Золотой Орды есть Если нет значит вы
still legally in the Golden Horde
юридически в Золотой Орде ещё находитесь
Hello How old are you guys,
Здравствуйте Сколько вам лет пацаны
guys, we are 18 Let's offer
пацаны нам по 18 Давайте предлагай
Cool Oh, that's your flag That's the
Прикольно О это у вас флаг Это империи
Romanov Empire Yes Yes, only with some other
Романовых Да Да только ещё с какими-то
inscriptions They had no inscriptions there
надписями Там у них же без надписей было
Got it Well, come on, turn around Cool
Понял Ну давай давай обернись Прикольно
You're cold Listen, what is the purpose of a
Тебе холодно Слушай а вот для чего нужен
flag, a
флаг
flag, well, to present the state
флаг ну чтобы государство презентовать
its Got it And why do you put it on
своё Понял И а что ж ты его надеваешь на
yourself, how or whose, not what, you
себя как или чей не а что ты для се
threw it on yourself like a cloak,
накинул на себя как плащ его
well, this particular flag is needed In
ну именно этот конкретно флаг нужен
short, I'm proud of them Interesting Interesting
Это короче горжусь я ими Интересно
Can you explain why you are
Интересно А можешь объяснить почему ты
proud of this
гордишься этим
flag because, in short, when the
флагом потому что короче когда на
Poles attacked Ukraine, the Ukrainians
Украину там поляки нападали украинцы
came and said: "Help us, please,
типа пришли говорят: "Помогите плиз
help us, they are trampling us there, crushing us, like,
помогите нам нас там топчут давят типа
what kind of empire was there,
вот это какая там была-то империя
Lithuanian, Polish In short, it doesn't matter  I've
литовская польская Короче без разницы я
already forgotten all of this That's it, the Russians,
уже забыл это всё Вот то это русские
in short, took them into the team and saved them and
короче в состав взяли и спасли и
kicked everyone there Cool Look where you
отпинали там всех Прикольно Смотри ты
come from
сам родом откуда
I come from Russia and St. Petersburg
я сам родом из России и Санкт-Петербурга
No, where did your parents
Не ну в Питер твои родители откуда
come to St. Petersburg [music] They were born natives
приехали в Питер они родились коренные
If they are natives then they are not Russian
Если коренные то они не русские потому
because the native population of St. Petersburg is not Russian
что коренное население Питера не русские
Swedes Germans Lithuanians and all sorts Yes, but not
Шведы немцы литовцы всякие Да но не
Russian So who are you by nationality
русские То ты кто по национальности
I'm Russian Well, look at your face
я русский Ну ты посмотри на своё лицо
What kind of Russian are you What did you
Какой ты русский
not like my face
Чем тебя ва чем ваш моё лицо не устроило
better dress Who do I look like Well, I
лучше одене На кого я похож
understand
ну чем понял
Look, can you tell me who your
смотри можешь мне сказать кем были твои
ancestors were in the Russian Empire
предки в Российской империи
My ancestors no I can't say I don't know
мои предки нет не могу сказать не знаю
Well, let me think about it they were an
Ну они давай так подумаю они были
emperor nobles or serfs I
императором дворянами или холопами
don't
не
know how I should know when the empire
знаю что мне откуда знать империя когда
was 200 years ago Well, that's right If
200 лет назад была Ну правильно Если бы
you were of noble birth yes then you would have
ты был дворянского рода да то ты бы
seen your ancestors in some chronicles
видел своих предков в летописях каких-то
in noble books and so on I
там в книгах дворянских и так дальше Я
understand that they  were not nobles but
так понимаю что они были не дворянами а
serfs Yes, let
холопами Да
's say Let's say Question Why are you
допустим Допустим Вопрос Почему же ты
happy that, uh, in the Romanov Empire,
радуешься что вот ээ в империи Романовых
yes, your ancestors were serfs and you are proud of
да твои предки были холопами и гордишься
this flag
этим флагом
Well, why shouldn't I be happy
ну так а что мне не радоваться
Well, look, I'm happy for my nation
ну смотри твои я радуюсь за свою нацию
So, what does this empire have to do with your
Так а причём тут это империя к твоей
nation
нации
Roman The Romanovs were Germans The emperors were
романо Романовы были немцами императоры
Germans The empire here is that I was
были немцами Империя тут то что я
born in this state This
родился в этом государстве это
state Look, what does the nation have to do with it Look, the
государство Смотри так а нация при чём
thing is that this empire was
смотри дело в том что эта империя была
German What's the difference the emperors
немецкая Что какая разница императоры
were Germans and the nobles were Germans, the
были немцы да дворяне были немцы
French, the Tatars, in short What do you have to do with it What do I have to do with it I was
французы татары короче А ты причём тут
born in this
что тут причём я я родился в этом
state This state was worth In
государстве Это государство стоило В
what state were you born of
каком ты государстве родился
this state that you have a flag on you
этого государства которое у тебя на тебя
in 1917 ceased to
флаг в 1917 году закончило своё
exist
существование
I know but it continued to
Я знаю но оно продолжило своё
exist I mean it continued the Russian Empire did not
существование В смысле продолжило
continue its
российская империя не продолжила своё
existence The
существо
SR USSR is the direct successor of the Russian
СР СССР прямой наследник Российской
Empire No, no Look in what year the
империи Нет нет Смотри в каком году
USSR appeared in the
появился СССР
twenty-fourth In  twenty-
двадцать четвёртом В двадцать
second A second to A The Russian Empire
втором А втором до А Российская империя
ceased to exist in the
закончила своё существование в
seventeenth Uh, if you had said in the Soviet
семнадцатом Ээ если б ты в Советском
Union that the Soviet Union was the
Союзе сказал что Советский Союз - это
successor to the Russian Empire, you would have been
наследник Российской империи тебя бы
shot,
расстреляли
no, Comrade Stalin would have shot you,
ну нет товарищ Сталин тебя бы расстрелял
like
как
Well, the Soviet Union is the Soviet Union,
Ну Советский Союз - это Советский Союз
but it has nothing to do with the Russian Empire
да он не имеет к отношению к Российской
All representatives of the Russian
империи Всех представителей Российской
Empire were
империи
shot All who said that we were an
порасстреливали Всех кто говорил что мы
empire The remnants who were not shot fled
империя Остатки недострельные поубегали
to NATO countries Yes, France, the
в страны НАТО Да Францию
USA, into exile Well, the
США в эмиграцию
territories remained the same
Ну так территории-то те же остались
In general, the people were the same So maybe
Вообще люди те же вообще Так так может
you look like that then you are the Golden Horde
вы так смотри тогда вы золотая орда
No Yes, the territories are the same, the people are the same
Нет Да территории те же люди те же
No, then there was a Russian state that was
Нет тогда было российское государство на
attacked by the Golden Horde, captured,
которое напала Золотая Рда захватила
then they left Look, look, it is golden, the
потом они ушли Смотри с смотри золотая
Golden Horde, yes it was Then the territories are the
Золотая Орда да была Потом территории те
same, all the same When Russia appeared
же всё те же Когда появилась Россия
after Russia freed itself from the
после когда Россия освободилась от
Golden Horde,
Золотой Орды
but I don’t know, it’s been a long time Well, it never happened
а я не знаю давненько Ну всё не было
Never freed You You are the
Никогда не освободил Вы Вы и есть
Golden Horde
Золотая Орда
no Yes, the capital just moved to
нет Да просто столица перекочевала в
Moscow
Москву
Well, look  1240 no 1238 yes for the
Ну смотри ты 1240 го нет 1238 год да за
capture of Moscow Everything When you when do you have a
захват Москвы Всё Когда вы когда у вас
day of independence from the Golden Horde
день независимости от Золотой Орды есть
or not no No Everything because you are the
или нет нет Нет Всё потому что вы есть
successor of the Golden Horde
продолжателем Золотой Орды
No Well yes Look again Moscow
Нет Ну да Смотри ещё раз Москва
submitted to the Golden Horde
подчинилась Золотой Орде
Princes of Moscow yes all these went
Князья московские да вот эти все ездили
to the Golden Horde in Saraibat and so on
в Золотую Орду в Сарайбату и так дальше
yes on bow like they received a label for
да на поклон типа получали ярлык на
book If you say that you left the
книжение Если ты говоришь что вы вышли
Golden Horde and then tell me when uh
из Золотой Орды и тогда скажи когда ээ
your state declared independence
ваше государство объявило независимость
from the Golden Horde
от Золотой Орды
yes I don’t know when it declared it
да не знаю когда оно объявил же
Well look I can clearly say about my state
Ну смотри я про своё государство могу
Look we uh in uh 1240 the
чётко сказать Смотри мы ээ в ээ 1240
Mongols captured China for the Tatar-Mongols
году монголы за татара-монголы захватили
yes 2 years after you Then Prince
Ки да через 2 года после вас Потом князь
Olgert this uh Lithuanian yes recaptured
Ольгерт этот ээ литовский да отвоевал
these territories from the Tatar-Mongols and uh the
эти территории у татаро-монгол и ээ
state of the Principality of
создалось государство княжество
Lithuanian Russian and Samogitian yes was created,
Литовское Русское и Жемайтийское да в
which we entered as Rus' Here Then
которое входили мы как Русь Вот Потом
this state through the union  united
это государство через унию объединилось
with the Poles and became the Polish-Lithuanian Commonwealth Yes, we
с поляками и стала Речь Посполитая Да мы
were in one state Then,
были в одном государстве Потом
as a result of,
вследствие
uh, various contradictions,
ээ разных противоречий
uh, part of our elite made, let's say, an
э-э часть нашей элиты сделала скажем
uprising then the war of Bohdan
восстание тогда войны войны Богдана
Khmelitsky yes from this in this
Хмелицкого да от ээ в это в этом
state yes and in fact separated
государстве да и фактически отделилась
yes independence Then, uh, we were absorbed by the
да независимость Потом ээ нас поглотила
Russian Empire Now, in
Российская империя Теперь вот мы в 1917
1917, we declared our independence
году провозгласили свою независимость
Then we were again absorbed by the Soviet Union, the
Потом снова нас поглотил Советский Союз
Soviet power, Russian Then in
советская власть российская Потом в 1991
1991, we declared independence from the
году мы провозгласили независимость от
Soviet Union Yes Here's the question If
Советского Союза Да Вот вопрос Если вам
I can clearly tell you yes when they captured when
я чётко могу да когда захватывали когда
independence capture independence everything
независимость захват независимость всё
yes clearly You were captured by the
да чётко Вы вас в 1238 году захватили
Tatar-Mongols in 1238 yes when you freed yourself
татаро-монгол да когда вы освободились
here is the year and day when you declared
вот год день когда вы провозгласили
independence from the Golden Horde is there if
независимость от Золотой Орды есть если
not then you are still legally in the Golden Horde Are
нет значит вы юридически в Золотой Орде
you talking about something well, wait
находитесь Вы какую-то порите ну подожди
again Look, any country, for example,
ещё раз Смотри любая страна например вот
Portugal, we can open declared
Португалия можем открываем объявила
independence then and there the USA
независимость тогда-то там США
declared independence from
провозгласила независимость от
Great Britain When did you declare
Великобритании Когда вы провозгласили
independence from  The Golden Horde The
независимость от Золотой Орды
Golden Horde has not existed for a long time What are
золотой Орды уже давно не существует Что
you talking about Look, when did you
ты несёшь так смотри когда вы
declare independence from it When did
провозгласили независимость от неё когда
you become independent
вы стали независимой
When did it fall apart Well, sometime Well, when
когда она распалась Когда
not If it Look,
ну когда-то ну когда не если она смотри
if you say it fell apart there and
если вот ты говоришь она распалась там и
that's it When did you become an independent
всё Когда вы стали независимым
state When did it
государством
fall apart When did that happen
когда она распалась когда это было когда
Give me my phone number
дай мой телефон
and I'll tell you When did it fall apart
а я тебе скажу когда она распалась
In 1721 the Golden Horde fell apart and
В 1721 году распалась Золотая Орда и
Peter I proclaimed the Russian Empire
Пётр I провозгласил Российскую империю
Well, you know Well, that's it That is Look, it
Ну знаешь ну вот и всё То есть смотри
turns out that from 1240 to
получается а с 1240 года до
1721 you were in the Golden Horde
1721 вы были в Золотой Орде
Well, not all Question Question When did the
ну не все Вопрос Вопрос Когда распалась
Golden Horde fall apart in 1721 Why did Peter I
в 1721 году Золотая Орда почему Пётр I
declare independence He simply
провозгласил независимость он просто
called this territory the Russian
назвал эту территорию Российской
Empire but did not declare
империей но не провозгласил
independence Why Because the Golden
независимость Почему потому что Золотая
Horde Just So And what is this that gives me
Орда просто Так И что это мне даётся вы
Where are you leading me to Because uh Peter I
меня к чему ведёте потому что ээ Пётр I
renamed the Golden Horde to the Russian
переименовал Золотую Орду в Российскую
empire Political center rolled
империю Политический центр перекатил
Peter I you were who by nationality was
Пётр Iвы он же был кто по национальности
German
е немец был
Well okay let's assume further that here uh he
Ну ладно допустим дальше что вот ээ он
laid down this made an alliance with the Tatars yes
уклал этот заключил союз с татарами да
that they are moving the capital they will build a new
что переносят столицу построят новую
capital
столицу
on the Neva they called it Petersburg Here he was a
на Неве назвали её Петербург Вот он был
prince uh accepted uh this
князь ээ принял ээ этот
rank prince title prince of Mongolia and that's
сан князь титул князь монгольский да и
all And you are the successor of the Golden Horde
всё И вы есть продолжателем Золотой Орды
You never declared independence from the
Вы не объявляли никогда независимость от
Golden Horde Peter I in 1721 did not
Золотой Орды Пётр I в 1721 году не
declare independence from the Golden Horde but
объявил независимость от Золотой Орды а
simply the Golden Horde renamed itself the
просто Золотая Орда переименовалась в
Russian Empire
Российскую империю
What is this all about what nonsense So what is this nonsense
Что к чему это вообще бред какой Так к
Well I'm telling you how when did
чему бред ну я же говорю как когда
your independent state appear when
появилось ваше
Oh it appeared independent Well
Ой оно и так и появилось независимое Ну
independently Well look again here I'm
независимо Ну ещё раз смотри вот я ещё
telling you again 1.23 988 In 988
раз говорю 1.23 988 году В 988 году
this prince of Kiev Vladimir baptized
князь этот Киевский Владимир крестил
Rus You were not yet in Pomine there were no
Русь Вас тогда ещё в Помине не было
Muscovites there somewhere in the swamps
московитов там где-то на на болотах
Moscow was not even there yet
Москвы ещё не было даже
And the Golden Horde has not yet arrived
И Золотая Орда не пришла ещё Русских не
There are no Russians Show me the Russians in the chronicles There
Покажи мне там русских в летописях
were no Russians in the territory
Никаких русских не было на территории
where you live now Finno-Ugric
где вы сейчас живёте там финоугорские
tribes lived there For example, look at the year 988
племена жили Вот например смотри 988 год
and Prince Vladimir Krestet Rus and
да князь Владимир Крестет Русь да
open the history textbook and look at the
открываем учебник истории и смотрим на
territory of modern Ukraine lived
территории современной Украины жили
Slavic tribes Polyane Drevlyane Ulich
славянские племена поляне древляне улич
Severyane Tivertsi and so on and on they
северяне тиверцы и так дальше да на
lived on the territory of Belarus and there Krivichi
территории Беларуси жили да там кривичи
and so on Which Slavic tribes
и так дальше Какие славянские племена
lived on the territory of the Moscow region
жили на территории Московской области
Vologda region Rostov this is oh
Вологодской области Ростовской это ой
Kostroma Vladimir At least
Костромской Владимирской Хоть одно
name one Slavic tribe
назови Племя славянское
Russians Russians There was no such
Русские русские Не было такого
Slavic tribe What are
славянского племени
you getting at? You can get closer
Не вы к чему клоните вы уже можете ближе
to the point I'm saying that you are not you are not
к делу Я говорю что вы вы не вы не
Slavs there We are Rus and you I don't know
славяне там Мы Русь а вы я не знаю
somehow Finno-Ugric tribes Turkic
как-то финоугорские племена тюркские
tribes are different Well, really, look I'm
племена разные Ну реально смотри я ж
just saying it's very simple Let's open the
просто говорю это очень просто Откроем
year 988 baptism of Rus On the territory of
988 год крещение Руси На территории
modern Ukraine live Slavic
современной Украины живут славянские
tribes
племена
like these I am the Drevlyans Polyane
эти как они я же древляне поляне
Severyane Uliversy then there Bili-Chorvaty
северяне уличверсы потом там Билихорваты
and a whole bunch more Yes Question on the territory of
ещё куча всего Да Вопрос на территории
modern yours there Moscow
современных ваших этих там Московской
region Kostroma Vladimir where did
области Костромской Владимирской откуда
your Russia come from
там ваша Россия вроде пошла хоть одно
name me at least one Slavic tribe You
назви мне славянское племя Ты же вот
went to school
учился в школе
What can I
Чток сейчас
say now For example, let's take the Drevlyans
скажу Вот например возьмём древляне У
They had a capital city Iskorostan
них был город столица Искоростань
modern Korostyn Polyane they had
современный Коростынь Поляне у них был
uh the capital Kyiv and the Severyane Vyatichi Vyatichi
ээ столицей Киев да Северяне вятичи
Vyatichi did not live there at all Even in
Вятичи Вятичи не жили там вообще Аж в
Moscow region they did not
Московской об не в Московской области не
live in the 10th century Tell me the city of
жили в X веке никие Скажи мне город
Vyatichi is the capital of Vyatichi Krivichi is
Вятичей столица Вятиче Кривичи - это
Belarus Krivichi is Belarus Polos
Беларусь Кривичи - это Беларусь Полос
Smolensk is in short far from you Tell
Смоленск это короче до вас далеко Скажи
me at least one city of Vyatichi here is a
мне вот хоть один город вятичей вот
Slavic city of that time at least
славянский город того того времени хоть
one
один
now I will tell you Come on
сейчас скажу Давай
In the 10th
В 10
century I am telling you the city of the Northerners here is
веке Вот я же говорю северяне город вот
Novgorod Seversky there is this Chernigov
Новгород Северский там вот этот Чернигов
and the Polyane Kyiv is the capital  Drevlyani And Kono
да поляне Киев столица Древляни И Коно
What is Korno What is Korno What is Korno Kordno Where is
Что корно Что корно Что корно Кордно Где
Korno city Where is this city Korno
это Корно город Где этот город Корно
it is
он
Kaluga region He went Kordno
это Калужской области Он шёл Кордно
Come on
Давай
City Vyatichi Come on Don't look
Город Вятичий Давай Не посмотри
Moscow region Here is Moscow
Московская область Вот Московская
region Vladimir region yes This is
область Владимирская область да Вот это
where your Russia came from name me
откуда пошла ваша Россия назови мне там
at least one Slavic city there in the 10th century and
хоть один славянский город в X веке да и
at least one tribe that lived there what are
хоть одно племя которое там жило
you getting at tell me already
что вы к чему клонитесь скажите мне уже
that there are no Slavic cities yes at
что никаких славянских городов да на
some kind of nonsense to me different Bo well how
какой-то мне бред несу разный Бо ну как
if there is no different nonsense name me in the
если бред нету разный назови мне в
Moscow region or in the Vladimir
Московской области или во Владимирской
region at least one Slavic city in the
области хоть один славянский город в
tenth
десято
century what Slavic tribe lived there
веке какое славянское племя там жило да
and what city they had
и какой город у них был
what I don't know because there was no
что я не знаю потому что не было Вот
Look in Google
посмотри в Гугле
Take Take in Google Slavic cities
Возьми возьми в Гугле славянские города
in the Moscow region 10th century Come on Well
в Московской области X век Давай
what was there not what are you getting at
Ну что не было что к чему вы клоните
I say that look on the territory of the
я говорю что смотри на территории
modern Moscow region
современной Московской области
Vladimir Vologda and so on yes they
Владимирской Вологодской и так дальше да
lived  not Slavs lived Finno-Ugric
жили не славяне жили финоугорские
tribes Ves Merya and Meshchera and so on and
племена Весь Меря и Мещера и так дальше
so forth, but as a result of uh centuries, uh,
да вот которые в результате э-э столетий
speaking the language
да э-э разговаривать на том языке
that is now called Russian, yes, it
который сейчас называется русский да
evolved But they are not Slavs and
эволюционировал Но они не славяне и к
have nothing to do with Rus' The
Руси никакого отношения не имеют
only thing is that they paid tribute to
Единственное что они там дань платили
Rus' The prince came and took their money That's
Руси Приезжал князь забирал у них бабки
all And
Вот и всё
what should I do now, nothing You
И что теперь мне сделать ничего
can cry,
Поплакать можешь
cry What's the point and the fact that you don't
поплакать Что к чему а то что типа вы не
consider this option From Nizhny
рассматриваете такой вариант Из Нижнего
Novgorod they all flocked there From
Новгорода они все стянулись туда Вот из
Nizhny Novgorod Nizhny Novgorod is a
Нижнего Ново Нижний Новгород - это
territory that was inhabited by
территория которая заселена была
Tatars, Chuvashes and Morians Look at the
татарами чувашами и морийцами Посмотри
Nizhny Novgorod region, even the census of
Нижегородская область даже перепись ээ
this Russian Empire, yes, who lived
этой Российской империи да кто там жил
there, Chuvashes, Morians, Tatars lived there
там жили чуваши морийцы татары
Well, when they lived there before the beginning,
Ну когда они там жили-то до начала-то
Russians lived there When Russians lived there
русские там жили Когда русские жили там
always There were never any Russians there in my life There are
всегда Никогда там в жизни русских не
still a lot of Tatars there, a lot even with
Там до сих пор куча татар куча даже с
your
вашей
Russification from Nizhny  Novgorod
русификацией из Нижнего Новгорода
some Russians What tribe of Slavs lived
какие-то русские Какое племя славян жило
in Nizhny Novgorod
в Нижнем Новгороде
tell me it's very simple Look I
скажи это же очень просто Посмотри я
take and call the tribes Slavic
беру и называю племена славянский
that are alive Why are you getting at the fact that
которые живы жи Почему вы клоните то что
Russians do not exist or that uh I'm getting
русских не существует или что ээ я клоню
at the fact that uh the modern term
к тому что ээ современным термином
Russian is like Americans yes in the USA the
русский это вот как американцы да в США
term Americans call just a bunch of
термином американцы называют просто куча
different peoples who live in the
разных народов которые живут в
United States of America Also the
Соединённых Штатах Америки Также и
Russians call this term a bunch of
русские этим термином называют куча
different peoples
разных народов
who lived in this territory
которые жили на этой территории
mixed and
посмешивались и
adopted the Church Slavonic language which was
приняли церковно-славянский язык который
based on Old Bulgarian from which the
на основе староболгарского был из
modern
которого развился современный как бы
Russian developed That is you for example
русский То есть ты например да
yes if you are a native Leningrader
вот если ты с коренной ленинградец
most likely you are from the tribe of the Vebs yes for
скорее всего ты из племени вебцев да
example the people of the Veptsy was yes
например народность такая Вепцы было да
it is not a tribe yes the people of the Veptsy That's
это не племя да народность вепцы
normal Putin is also a Veps Nothing wrong with
Вот нормально Путин тоже Вепс Ничего
that Well maybe maybe
страшного в этом нет Вот может может ещё
not yet Well a little bit not this not that
не Ну чуть-то нечуть не это не то
a little bit Here are all sorts of in the Moscow region
немножко Вот всякие в Московской области
yes the tribe of Merya lived  Here is Moscow
да жило племя меря Вот московско
Volgodskoe, all the names of the rivers, yes, in
Волгодское оно все названия рек да в
these territories they are Finno-Ugric, not
этих территориях финоугорские не
Slavic, because
славянские потому что там жили
Finno-Ugric tribes lived there. And everything is very
финоугорские племена И всё ведь очень
simple. All the talk about which of
просто Все разговоры о том кто там из
us is Rus ends with a simple question:
нас Русь оканчивается простым вопросом:
what Slavic tribe lived in those
какое племя славянское жила на тех
territories? If we take modern
территориях если мы берём современную
Ukraine, right here, even in our
Украину вот прямо у нас даже в учебнике
history textbook, you immediately open here such a tribe,
истории сразу открываешь тут такое племя
here such a tribe, here such a tribe, Belarus such a tribe,
тут такое тут такое Беларусь такое такое
Russia, no Slavic tribe lived in the Moscow region. No
Россия в Московской области никакое
Slavic tribe lived in the Kostroma region. No Slavic tribe
области никакое славянское племя не
lived in the Vladimir region, where did the
жило В Владимирской области откуда там
Vladimir-Suzdal principality come from?
Владимирско-Суздальское княжество
Blah-blah-blah, no Slavic tribe
бла-бла-бла никакое славянское племя не
lived there.
жило
And what did you want to convey to me now?
И что вы мне сейчас этим донести-то
Well, that Russians are not Slavs.
хотели ну что русские не славяне
This is nonsense. Why, well, I do
Это бред Почему
n’t know. You are different Finno-Ugric
ну не знаю Вы разные финоугорские
Turkic peoples who simply
тюркские народы которые просто
speak a language, uh, which came
разговаривают на языке ээ который пошёл
from the Slavic group. That’s
из славянской группы Вот и
all. Just like look now, for example,
всё Так же как смотри сейчас например
when  Buryats yes Buryats uh they forget
когда бурятов да бурятов ээ они забывают
their language and start speaking Russian
свой язык и начинают говорить по-русски
they don't become Russians from this
они же от этого не стают русскими
though well we just visually see that
правда ну просто мы визуально видим да
they are Buryats Well they just
что они буряты Ну просто по-русски
speak Russian And all these peoples who
говорят Так и все эти народы которые
lived in this territory yes they uh
жили на этой территории да они э-э
Russified in the sense that uh they started
русифицировались в плане что э-э стали
speaking the dialect uh
говорить на наречии ээ
Church Slavonic language which is
церковно-славянского языка который
now called Russian yes because
сейчас именуется русским да потому что
Pushkin invented the language for you Before that all the
вам Пушкин придумал язык До этого вся
nobility spoke French yes they
знать говорила на французском да
spoke German Well these are
говорила на немецком
some myths What myths well the
Ну так это какие-то мифы Какие мифы
fact that Great Russians do not belong to the
ну то что великоросы не принадлежат к
Slavs There are
числу славян
no Great Russians
Никаких великоросов не существует Это в
This term was invented yes in the Russian
этот термин придумали да в Российской
Empire in order to somehow
империи чтобы короче себе как-то так
make some kind of base for themselves Well and then they came up with it
сделать какую-то базу Ну а держали пото
Maybe it was invented in Ukraine
придумали Может это в Украине придумали
by some tribes tribes were Show
по какие-то племена племена были Покажи
not tribes Look we are opening the chronicles
не племена Смотри мы открываем летописи
All the tribes exist We are opening the chronicles of
Все племена есть Мы открываем летописи
neighboring peoples Yes these tribes exist It's
соседних народов Да племена эти есть Вот
all
всё
simple And where in what chronicles are the Great Russians
просто А великоросов где в каких
Great Russians are nowhere  there are no
летописях есть великоросы нигде никаких
Great Russians This was invented already under
нету великоросов Это придумано уже при
these, that's when you put this flag on it
этих при вот это когда этот флаг у тебя
again It was necessary to
снова Нужно было какой-то миф
make some kind of state myth Here they came up with
государственный делать Вот придумали
some
каких-то
Great Russians You are fighting some kind of
великоросов Вы какую-то борите
Why
Почему
look in Russia there is a city of
вот смотри в России есть город
Murom What does the name Muram
Муром Что он означает название Мурам
Ilya Muromets mean No, it means there was
илья Муромец Нет это означает вот было
such a tribe of Murom Look at the tribe of Murom Here
такое племя Мурома Посмотри вот племя
you are on Google now Well, okay Well, the
Мурома Вот на Гугле ты же сейчас Ну
Finno-Ugric tribe of Murom yes
хорошо Ну финоугорское племя Мурома да
What does the Russian city of
Что означает русский город
Ryazan mean is a city of the Erzya tribe
Рязань это город племени Эрзя
Finno-Ugric
Финоугорского
[music]
[музыка]
What are you actually waiting a minute Come on
Что вы вообще-то подождите минуту
Bedlaga
Давай Бедлага
Yes
Да
Conducted the denocification of the orc
Провёл деноцификацию орка
[music]
[музыка]
Well, so what do you want to tell me
Ну так и что вы мне хотите сказать
Russians are not Slavs
русский не славяне
yes
да
Russians are a conglomerate of completely
Русские - это конгломерат из абсолютно
different ethnic groups that now speak the
разных этносов которые сейчас говорят на
language of the Slavic group That's
языке славянской группы Вот и
all It's very simple Look if uh Russians are
всё Очень просто Смотри если ээ русские
Slavs if there is such an ethnic group Russian yes
славяне если есть такой этнос русский да
uh there is then Russian culture Here you
ээ есть тогда русская культура Вот
can tell me for example  at least one
можешь мне назвать например хоть одну
Russian wedding song, here is a Ukrainian one, I
русскую свадебную песню вот украинскую я
can name you There burn the salmon poled Oh,
могу назвать Там гори лосос наполала Ой
on the mountain, two oak trees, there she there And can you
на горе два дубки там ше там А можешь
name me at least one Russian folk wedding
мне назвать хоть одну русскую свадебную
song, they have
песню
arrived
народную приехали
[music] It's
[музыка]
true that every nation, if it has a
Правда вот у каждого народа если он есть
formed ethnic group, has
этнос сформированный да у него есть
folk art, songs, and so
народное творчество песни да и так
on And can you name me a Russian
дальше Вот можешь мне назвать русскую
wedding, Russians, everything No, look, the thing is that there are
свадьбу русские всё Не вот смотри дело в
Mari wedding songs, there are
том что марийские свадебные песни есть
Tatar wedding songs, there are
татарские свадебные песни
Erzemoksha, and there are Mordvin wedding
есть Эрземокша да мордовские свадебные
songs And
песни есть А русскую хоть одну русскую
name me at least one Russian wedding song, well,
свадебную песню назови мне
I don't know because there isn't
ну да я и не знаю потому что нет
Try on Google, maybe you'll remember On
Попробуй на Гугле может вспомнишь На
Google, Russian wedding folk
Гугле русская свадебная народная
wedding song On Google Well, on Google,
свадебная песня На Гугле
what, on Google, tell me which one Well, there isn't, there isn't,
Ну на Гугле что ну на Гугле скажи какая
and what isn't, you see, there isn't, So
Ну нету нету И что нету Видишь нету Так
look, there are Polish, there are Czechs, there are
смотри польский есть да чешские есть
Ukrainians, there are Belarusians, yes,
украинский есть белорусский есть да
why, because there are such nationalities,
почему потому что есть такие народности
and Russian is like an American, yes,
а русский - это как вот американец да
that's it  there is such an ethnos Americans no there
вот есть такой ээ этнос американцы нет
are Irish
там есть ирландцы
eh Scots English Germans Spaniards yes
ээ шотландцы англичане немцы испанцы да
different people they are called Americans by a
разный народ они называются американцы
common name So Russians - this is
общим названием Так вот русские - это
how Americans at one time
как американцы это в своё время
called the population of this territory
назвали население вот этой территорией
which consists of absolutely different peoples That's
которая из абсолютно разных народов
all Now I'll simplify the task for you
всё Теперь я тебе упрощу задачу
can if there is such an ethnos yes Russian
можешь если есть такой этнос да русский
here as a people and not as just a
вот как народ а не как просто
conglomerate of different peoples called
конгломерат разных народов названный
such a name can you name me not a
такой назва можешь мне назвать не
wedding song but just at least a Russian
свадебно а вот просто хотя бы русскую
folk song you can name about five
народную песню штук пять можешь назвать
In Opale a Birch Tree Stood In Opole a Birch Tree
В Опале Берёзка стояла В ополе Берёзка
Stood an author's song Look in
стояла авторская песня Посмотри в
Google
Гугле
[music] Right
[музыка]
now
Сейчас прямо
Oh frost frost below zero When stop stop stop stop
Ой мороз мороз подонуля Когда стоп стоп
Oh frost No look no Oh frost
стоп стоп Ой мороз Нет смотри не Ой
frost - this is a Ukrainian song Now
мороз мороз - это украинская песня Вот
take it now on Google oh frost frost
возьми сейчас на Гугле ой мороз мороз
this is a Ukrainian song Google Oh frost frost Come on Oh frost
это украинская песня Нагугли Ой мороз
Look at the song You're not the first one with whom this has
Смотри песня Ты же не первый с кем это
already happened Everything is propaganda for you there
уже проходи У тебя там всё пропаганда
No  no no Look look for yourself
Нет нет нет Посмотри посмотри сам
Wikipedia Oh frost-frost Type in and read
Википедии Ой мороз-мороз Вбей и прочитай
Here Oh frost frost Ukrainian folk
Вот Ой мороз мороз Украинская народная
song The author of the Russian version of the song
песня Автором русского варианта песни
is Maria Pavlovna Uvarova, the wife of the
является Мария Павловна Уварова супруга
first performer of the song, Alexander
первого исполнителя песни Александра
Mikhailovich Uvarov In 1950 in the 20th century,
Михайловича Уварова В 1950 в XX веке
she sang in Russian Here type in Oh frost
перепела она по-русски Вот вбей Ой мороз
frost Wikipedia will
мороз Википедия тебе
show you Read Russian folk songs Don't
покажет Читай Русские народные песни Не
read Oh frost frost Write type in
прочитай Ой мороз мороз Напиши вбей в
Google Oh frost frost don't freeze me Don't
Google Ой мороз мороз не морозь меня Не
frost Open open Write Wikipedia Oh
мороз Открой открой Напиши Википедия Ой
frost frost
мороз мороз
Opened Source Russian folk songs
Открыл Источник русские народные песни
No again Okay Editorial text No
Нет ещё раз Окей Текст редакции Нет
Write Wikipedia Oh frost Frost
Напиши Википедия Ой мороз Мороз
opened the article Well, the
открыл статью
Wikipedia article is called:
Ну статья в Википедии так и называется:
"Oh frost frost" Yes Oh frost frost
"Ой мороз мороз" Да Ой мороз мороз
Russian folk song The author of the Russian
Русская народная песня Автором русского
version of the song is Don't you see, you
варианта песни является Не видишь ты
read it says Ukrainian There he
прочитал там написано украинская Там
wrote here here here there  a
написал вот вот вот там написана
Ukrainian folk song was written You read
украинская народная песня Ты прочитал
Russian specifically, yes, you
русское специально да
see, so look, I'm not deceiving you, what do you
видишь так смотри я же тебя не обма что
want to say? I'll explain. I see, the thing is,
хотите сказать Объясню Смотрю дело в том
look, look at me I'm dressed in a
что смотри посмотри на меня Я одет тоже
specific way too, yes, I'm a folklorist, yes, I have a
специфически да я фольклорист да я имею
higher education in this field, yes,
высшее образование в этой сфере да у
I have 18 years of practice, in 2 years I'll be
меня 18 лет практики через 2 года будет
twenty. By the way, I'm just
двадцаточка Да кстати вот я как раз
studying the folk art of the Slavic
изучаю народное творчество ээ славянских
peoples, including the territory of
народов и в том числе ээ территории
Russia, because there, various
России потому что там разные
non-Slavic peoples have adopted
неславянские народы приняли славянскую
some Slavic culture, yes. And so, you see,
некоторую культуру да И вот ты же видишь
you say: "Oh, frost, frost, you
ты говоришь: "Ой мороз мороз ты где-то
read it somewhere on Google." And I immediately say:
там в Гугле начитал" А я сразу говорю:
"No, look, check." Because this is a
"Нет смотри проверь" Потому что это
Ukrainian song that was simply
украинская песня которую просто в 1956
re-sung into Russian in 1956 under the Soviet Union.
году при Советском Союзе перепели на
That's all. And so a bunch of things. Yes, there
русский язык Вот и всё И так куча всего
is Black Raven - this is also not a
да Вот есть Чёрный Ворон - это тоже не
Russian folk song. This is an author's
русская народная песня Это ээ авторская
song of one soldier, published for
песня солдата одного в опубликованная
the first time in the newspaper Russian Disabled Person. You are
впервые в газете Русский инвалид Ты
not now  rye That's right Look in
сейчас не ржи Это так и есть Посмотри в
this Wikipedia song Black Raven and
этом в Википедии песня Чёрный ворон и
you'll see that the author is
посмотришь да что это автором есть
some officer Yes, that's all clear So that's what
какой-то там офицер Да это всё понятно
you're getting at with the question Yes
Так вот вы мне к чему клоните вопрос Да
Why do Ukrainians have thousands of folk songs
Почему украинцев есть народных песен
Poles have thousands of folk songs
тысячи у поляков народных песен - тысячи
Belarusians have thousands of folk songs
у белорусов народных песен - тысячи У
Lithuanians have thousands of folk songs but
литовцев народных песен тысячи а у
Russians do
русских народных
n't have any Well, is
нет Ну что
it that songs among us are Slavs
ли что песни у нас это славяне
measured in songs or what's the matter how it
измеряются в песнях или что вот как так
turns out that there are people but no folk art What
получается народ есть а народного
is folk art, I guess,
Что есть народное творчество поди
some kind of some kind Well, what is it that
какое-нибудь какое-нибудь
in songs it's something
ну что что в песнях это что-то
measured in some kind of yes, it's measured in songs
измеряется в каких-то да в песнях
yes Well, look people yes, uh,
измеряется да Ну смотри народ да ээ
folk culture is songs,
народная культура это же есть песни
folk dances Let's look at dances
народные танцы Давай посмотрим танцы Вот
I'll name Ukrainian dances Gapak Arkan
я украинские танцы назову Гапак аркан
Name me at least one Russian folk
Назови мне хоть один русский народный
dance
танец
No, I don't want to What are the dances enough songs for me a
Да не хочу я Что танцы песни хватит мне
person who gets caught
вам человек который попадает попадётся
who knows you in Ukraine to catch
который знает вам у в Украине поймать на
any schoolchild any adult on the street and
улице любого школьника любого взросла и
ask: "Name a Ukrainian folk
спросить: "Назви украинский народный
dance at least one." Pak as in any case will
танец хоть один." Пак как по-любому
say you Russian folk dance
скажет вы русский народный танец
name at least one I don't
назовите хоть один
know No No
не знаю Нету Нет
Name Russian national footwear
Назови русскую национальную обувь
MK Saran No here is an element of clothing Here are
Мк Саран Не вот элемент одежды Вот
Russian national footwear
русская национальная обувь
what valenki Valenki Not Russian Valenki
какая валенки Валенки Не русская Валенки
are a Turkic ob Rus No What were valenki
- это тюрская об Рус Нет Из чего валенки
made of it is me What were valenki made of
делались это я Из чего валенки делались
yes how do I know you what before me
да я откуда знаю вы что до меня
look you tell me what you are
смотри вы мне скажите к чему вы
leaning towards Valen now Valenki are
клонитесь Вален сейчас Валенки - это
Turkic footwear yes which came Tatars
тюркская обувь да которая пришла Татары
Kazakhs brought yes this footwear here
казахи принесли да вот эту обувь сюда
Valenki Russians don't have Russians have bast
Валенки У русских нет У русских вот есть
shoes Bast shoes are really
лапти Лапти - это действительно
national footwear Okay They
национальная обувь была Хорошо Из
made them from birch bark and so on Bast shoes yes
бересты лыка делали и так дальше Лапти
Then look don't put on that flag which
да То смотри не одень этот флаг который
you put on You were so childish at first with
ты одевал Ты вначале такой детский был с
this flag something there Ukraine Poles yes
этим флагом что-то там Украина поляки да
and now you are depressed I even liked it I am
а теперь приуныл Мне аж понравилось Я
so beautiful Well you are
так красиво Ну так вы мне какую-то
just messing with me You are already messing with my brain
просто порите Вы мне уже все мозги
zaputali What look look very
запудали Какие смотри смотрите очень
simple I ask what Slavic
просто Я спрашиваю какое славянское
tribe lived in those territories at least one
племя жило на тех территориях хоть одно
no I ask what Russian
нету Спрашиваю какие у вас русские
folk songs do you have No What Russian
народные песни Нету Какие русские
folk dances
народные танцы
no You have nothing Why because
нету Ничего у вас нету Почему потому что
it's an artificial term Who invented you
это искусственный термин Вас придумал
Lenin If you look before the
кто ленин Если ты посмотришь до
revolution yes even the term Russian was not
революции да даже термин русский нигде
used anywhere There was no
не использовался Не было
such thing Lenin and Stalin invented yes
такого Ленин со Сталиным придумали да
Russians because it was necessary
русских потому что нужно нужно было
somehow to
как-то
designate this this population Here
обозначать эту это население Вот
they came up with the name Russian
придумали название русский
And the term Ukrainians was also not
А термин украинцы тоже нигде не
used anywhere Ukrainians yes Look the term
использовался Украинцы да Смотри термин
Ukrainians yes uh was not used before
украинцы да ээ раньше не использовался
but it refers to those people who lived
но он относится к тем людям которые жили
in these territories At first we were
на этих территориях Сначала мы
called Rusyns but then uh they began to be
назывались русыны да вот потом ээ стали
called Ukrainians the same way as they used to be
называться украинцы так же как раньше
called for example uh Persians yes now
назывались например ээ персы да теперь
Iranians are called Before there were Romans but
иранцы называются Раньше были римляне да
now Italians for example And Russians what were
сейчас итальянцы например А русские как
you used to be called that's when
вы раньше назывались вот во времена
Moscow was made Ali no Look
когда Москву сдела Али никаких Смотри
Great Russians Great Russians this was invented already
великорос великороссы это придумали уже
in the Russian Empire Show
в Российской империи Покажи
me look when  Moscow was founded, for
мне вот смотри когда Москву основали
example, show me at least one word there "
например покажи мне там хоть одно слово
Velikoros" There were no "Velikoros" Well, they were
великорос Никаких великоросов не было Ну
called someone else, I don't know who They
кем-то другим называли я не знаю кем Так
weren't called anything at all There was no
не было вообще никак не называли Не было
such population There were tribes
там такого населения Там были племена
Merya Meshchera Murom
Меря Мещера Мурома
[music]
[музыка]
So what's next, then what's
Ну и что дальше-то
next, then the flag Don't raise this flag
дальше так флаг Не подними этот флаг
Raise the flag Why are you so shy, come on,
Подними флаг Что ты так стесняешься
put it on yourself Come on You see, you're hiding behind
давай нацепи на себя Давай Видишь ты
it You're shy
прячешься за него Ты стесняешься В глаза
Look me in the eyes So what, come on, sit like this
мне смотри Ну и что давай вот сиди вот
I like to burn these imperialists
так Мне нравится прожигать этих имперцев
with a flag Such So, uh, I'll tell you
с флагом Такое Так вот ээ я тебе скажу
about the tribes there
насчёт племён
was a tribe, but it was not Slavic, which
было племя но оно не славянское которое
lived on the territory of the Moscow and
жило на территории Московской и
Vladimir regions This tribe
Владимирской области Это племя
was called
называлось
Androphagia And when the
Андрофагия И когда
prince of Rus' came from Rus', he taxed the
Русь с Руси князь приходил он облагал
Androphages and taught them to read and write The thing is that,
Андрофагов и учил их грамоте Дело в том
well, you know, Herodotus wrote about the
что ну ещё знаешь Геродот писал о
Androphages that they
Андрофагах
were a very cruel, wild tribe
вот что очень жестокое дикое племя было
But
Но
through the historical process they were taught to
путём исторического процесса научили их
write  bukvits The idea is that where did the
писать буквицам Идея в том что откуда
letter come from you from Kyiv to Kyiv
пришло письмо у вас с Киева в Киев вот
these bukvits were brought by Cyril and Methodius from
эти буквицы принесли Кирилл и Мефодий с
Lake Ohrid in modern Macedonia
Охридского озера в современной Македонии
Then it was the Bulgarian kingdom yes
Тогда это было болгарское царство да
and from Kyiv the Kyiv monks went to
а из Киева киевские монахи шли
preach to different wild tribes
проповедовать по разным диким племенам в
including the tribes of the Androphagi, the tribes of
том числе племена андрофагов племена
Meri and so on and brought them a letter from
Мери и так дальше и несли им грамоту с
Kyiv bukvits
Киева
Before that you didn’t have any letters there How do
буквицы До этого у вас никаких букв там
you know tea name some
Откуда вы знаете чай назови какие-то
letters what letters you had There were none The
буквы какие у вас были Не
letter was brought to you from Rus' from Kyiv
было Грамоту принесли вам с Руси с Киева
Well so what do you want from me now
Ну так а что вы от меня хотите-то сейчас
I honestly
я честно говоря я от
want from you just so that you could
тебя хочу просто как бы чтобы ты ещё
sit a little longer I’m just enjoying I’m
подольше посидел Я просто наслаждаюсь Я
enjoying such de-nomination
наслаждаюсь такой деноцификацией
Enjoy No you are a person
Наслаждайтесь Нет вы есть человека
who knows for this to sort out in history
который знает за это чтобы в истории
He will tell all this We started
разбирать Он это всё расскажет Мы начали
we started with what you were dragging there You did
мы начали с тем что ты там тащил Ты же
n’t say: “Oh I’m just a person who
не сказал: "Ой я просто человек который
doesn’t understand history You started poking
не разбираюсь в истории Ты начал тыкать
this flag you are Ukrainians Poles and we
этот флаг вас там украинцы поляки а мы
you were released in short and then it turned out
вас короче освободили а тут оказалось
that I you yes I simply uh
что я тебя да я тебя просто ээ
historically
исторически
destroyed you" Do you know what it means
уничтожил" А знаешь что означает
look at the question uh in Russian
смотри вопрос ээ по русскому языку
Question in Russian What is the
Вопрос по русскому языку Какое какой
common root of the word destroyed and the
общий корень у слова слова уничтожил и у
word
слова
insignificance what is the common root here is the
[__] какой общий корень вот
question in Russian
вопрос по русскому языку
Yes, I'll check that Are you not a Slav
Да я проверим то Ты ты что не славянин
you don't understand the Slavic language here is
ты славянский язык не понимаешь вот
the word destroyed and the word nothing What is their
слово уничтожил и слово ничто Какой у
root insignificance and destroyed What is
корень [__] и и уничтожил Какой у
their common root
них общий корень
nothing Nothing yes Nothing So look as a
ничто Ничто да Ничто Так вот смотри я в
result of this conversation I
результате этого разговора твою эту
turned your pride and you into nothing that is
гордыню и тебя превратил в ничто то есть
zero Multiplied by zero
в ноль Умножил на ноль
Where did you get that from our conversation
С чего вы это взяли у нас разговор
began
начинался
Complete victory Popka This is what the
Полная перемога Попка Вот это провёл
denazification ceremony was like
обряд денацификации
Like subscribe comment and share with
Лайк підписка комент и розкиньте по
friends this Subscribe to the game right
друзям цеде Підпишись на йграam прям
now Os in A
зараз Ось вн А
popik is very very  YouTube is politely banning
попик це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube
us through Karger and
заганяе нас через каргер в тньовий бан И
even a lot of videos are not shown to people,
дуже багато відео не показуется людям
information about the stream is not shown at all times
вчасно не показуется інформація про
So in order to have a
стрими Тому для того щоб ми мали
quick connection, subscribe right
оперативный зв'язок підпишиться прямо
away And the pop there in telegram okmdeo is also the same
зараз А попик там в телеграмі окмдео ще
tsikava and korisna  Information and we are
теж цікава и корисна інформація и мы
responsible for you to maintain constant
повинні з вами тримати постійний
operational communication regardless of the fact that we will
оперативный зв'язок незалежно від того
show you about this YouTube Glory to
чи покаже вам про цей YouTube Слава
Ukraine subscribe
Україні підпишись